KARTIK CHAWLA

Toronto, ON L3R ◆ +1 (705) 500-4371 ◆ kchawla1995@gmail.com

Website, Portfolio, Profiles

Github Linkedin Website

Professional Summary

Software Engineer with 6 years of experience designing, testing, and developing software solutions. In depth understanding of web technologies with focus on delivering innovative business solutions. Excels in fast- paced, high-energy, and deadline-driven environment with willingness to take on additional tasks.

SKILLS

- JS Frameworks: React.js, Angular (2+), Vue.js
- SSR: Next.js, Angular Universal
- Source and Version Control: Git, GitHub, Gitlab, BitBucket
- JavaScript Expertise
- Scrum, Agile Methodology
- Front-End Skills: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Web Development
- Backend JS Framework: Node.JS

- Redux, NGRX
- Responsive Designs: Bootstrap, Material UI
- Unit Testing Frameworks: Jasmine, Karma, Jest
- End to End Testing: Cypress
- Databases: Oracle, SQL, MongoDB
- Cloud Computing: AWS, GCP
- · React Native
- · Kotlin Android
- Swift using Storyboard / SwiftUI iOS
- Restful API, GraphQL
- JIRA

WORK HISTORY

React JS Developer, 06/2022 - Current

- Demonstrated respect, friendliness, and willingness to help wherever needed
- Worked flexible hours, night, weekend, and holiday shifts.
- Used React.js + Next.js for SSR
- Used Redux to maintain user store and tokens

Senior Software Engineer, 04/2021 - 04/2022

EPAM Systems

- Created seamless UI for multiple projects using Angular (2+)
- Used NGRX to maintain state of the application
- Upgraded old projects to the latest angular version
- Used Angular Material to build responsive web applications
- Contributed to building a CDX Library for the client
- Build Lambda functions using Node JS
- Helped in building a strong UI Team by taking multiple interviews.

Senior Software Engineer, 08/2019 - 04/2021

Kellton Tech Solutions Private Limited

- Communicated with multiple clients directly for requirement gathering and development
- Used NGRX and RXJS extensively to maintain App state and user stores
- Went to Ireland for on-site development
- · Managed multiple teams as a lead
- Worked on Multiple projects simultaneously in different time zones (UK and US), as a single resource
- Setup AGILE methodology in a project acting as SCRUM Master and organizing all AGILE meetings.

Software Engineer, 02/2017 - 08/2019

Kellton Tech Solutions Private Limited

- It's a "Born Digital" technology consulting and IT services company that delivers innovative solutions
- Used NGRX and RXJS extensively to maintain App state and user stores
- Conducted training for Freshers in JavaScript, Angular and Node.js
- Wrote multiple Technical Blogs
- Created various POC's for showcasing to the clients.

- EDUCATION